# KATHARINA RISCHE

# **UI** Designer

Berlin I Germany

+49 17626928833 katharina.rische1@gmail.com katharinarische.myportfolio.com www.linkedin.com/in/katharinarische

#### **ABOUT ME**

It has always been natural to me to put myself in the shoes of others, empathize and find solutions to solve problems. My urge to take on a creative role joint with my problem solving and communication skills, I want to design intuitive and inspiring products for a positive user experience.

#### **SKILLS**

#### Design

Figma, Sketch, InVision, Adobe Photoshop, Balsamiq, Flinto

#### **Process**

User Research,
User Stories and Personas,
User Testing (A/B, Usability,
Preference),
Prototyping,
User Flows,
Wireframes,
Moodboards,
Style Guides,
Brand Guidelines

# Technical CSS, HTML, JavaScript

#### Language

German (native), English (fluent)

#### **HOBBIES**

Reading inspirational books, Drawing and painting (acryl, oil), Travel the world

# **EDUCATION**

## CareerFoundry GmbH UI Design Berlin, Germany September 2020 - Juni 2021

An intense UI Design project based training program with a focus on design principles, the UX and UI design process, mobile app design and branding.

#### **PROJECTS**

### TaskTracker I UI Design

- Developed a mobile app version of a productivity app with two to three key functionalities.
- Conducted a competitor analysis, built user flows, created low-fidelity to high-fidelity wireframes and applied the built style guide on the final screens.
- View project here

### TrackMap I UX/UI Design

- Built a recommendation-based responsive app and focused on the development of an application from the start to the finished product.
- Completed competitor analysis, user research and usability testing, then designed two mood boards and a style guide used for the final screens and mockups.
- View project here

#### Spiritly I UI Design

- Developed a native app for both iOS and Android to provide users with a platform and space to support them in their goal to become mentally strong and healthy.
- Created the user flows, wireframes, added mobile gestures as well as sounds and physical feedback and adapted the style guidelines for prototype testing. Implemented gathered feedback and enhanced the final screens and mockups.
- View project <u>here</u>

#### CuraePure I UI Design

- Designed the UI for an online store to help everyone find products quickly and easily to match their particular needs.
   Built the user flows and wireframes, based on the user stories.
- Completed the brand guidelines and applied those to the screens for prototyping and testing. Gathered feedback and enhanced the final screens and mockups.
- View project here

Udemy I Design Rules: Principles + Practices for Great UI Design a Certificate Course by Joe Natoli Berlin, Germany September 2020

Stenden Hoogeschool Bachelor of Business Administration I Hotel Management Leeuwarden, Netherlands February 2010 - February 2014

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Booking.com (Deutschland) GmbH I Account Executive Berlin, Germany I Since May 2017

- Advise 300+ business partners on current market trends and strengthen the relationship as the first point of contact in the highly competitive and dynamic tourism industry, with frequent performance calls and support with challenges. This results in positive feedback from business partners and shadowed calls by colleagues.
- Reached quarterly number of call targets with a minimum of 400 calls and actioned business opportunities, offering and implementing business solutions which contributed to the overachieved sales target for Germany.
- Contribute to the local marketing team with my organizational skills setting up and executing Webinars, to reach a designated but large number of 7000+ business partners in the DACH region, which resulted in strategic product implementations and positive survey results.

## Boeing Deutschland GmbH I Administrative Assistant Berlin, Germany I May 2016 - April 2017

- Guaranteed all office supplies in the three German branch offices were stocked sufficiently by receiving requests, checking inventory, placing orders and making sure a timely supply.
- All incoming and recurring invoices for the business in Germany needed to be paid punctually. Checked and correctly inserted invoices in the invoice management system daily, which resulted in on time payments.
- Monitored the waiting area, ensuring all incoming guests and employees are registered to ensure the security of the company.

## Adina Apartment Hotels I Receptionist and Night Audit Berlin, Germany I August 2015 - April 2016

- Performed security checks, ran the night audit reports in the property management system, checked the correct billing of all rooms as well as the city tax report and ensured a smooth handover for the day shift, as head of all departments during the night audit shifts.
- Provided a smooth check-in and check-out to guests, offering various help, to make all guests feel welcome and valued staying at the hotel, which summed in satisfied guests as well as contributed to positive social media reviews.

# Apex International Hotel I Receptionist and Supervisor Edinburgh, Scotland I February 2014 - August 2015

- Demonstrated proficiency in a high-volume work environment at the reception ensuring a smooth check-in and check-out of guests, welcoming them at the hotel and handling various payment method so guests felt valued and received a score of 100% by frequent external auditors.